<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xml" href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xslt.xml"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.3.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-07-28T19:37:18+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000//</id><title type="html">The Master’s University</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Senior Memoir: Kailey Richardson</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/news/burrito" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Senior Memoir: Kailey Richardson" /><published>2017-02-15T22:24:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-02-15T22:24:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/news/burrito</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/news/burrito">&lt;p&gt;Master’s was my last choice. Not only was it my last choice, but it was the only choice I tried to run away from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been around this school my entire life. I was born and raised in the Santa Clarita Valley. I grew up going to Placerita Bible Church, which is next to Masters, for the first seventeen years of my life. My parents were involved in the college group, my dad is an adjunct professor at Master’s, my mom would eventually work here for a period of time, and both my siblings went to the college. I cannot remember a time that I didn’t know of Master’s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It always seemed like an option to go here. Then, my sophomore year of high school, I lost my mom to cancer. It was then I began chasing the wrong things for comfort. When it came time to choose a college, I was determined to get away from the school so familiar to me. I gave plenty of reasons but the truth was I didn’t want the spiritual accountability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the Lord had it, all my attempts to go to a different school utterly failed. So August 17, 2013, I reluctantly came to WOW (Week of Welcome) Saturday, with every intention to transfer as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The transition was rough. I faked my way to fit in and my heart was at war with itself. Then, one night, I had a conversation with my Resident Assistant (RA) that permanently changed my life. We chatted and gave bits of our life stories before eventually sharing our full testimonies with one another. Towards the end, she told me she had been praying for me the past two years. She had gone to Outreach Week with my brother back in 2011 and he had given a prayer request for me. She was faithful to fulfill that request.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was stunned, thrown off guard and absolutely bewildered. Here was a girl, whom I had never met, who had been praying for me for two years. There was nothing I had ever been faithful enough to pray about for two whole years. She didn’t know if she would ever meet me, let alone that I would end up on her wing. And, yet, she petitioned the Lord on my behalf.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a gracious smack in the face. God had me here, exactly where I was, on that exact wing, in that exact dorm for a reason. Why was I fighting? If I was simply willing to let go, trust and submit, there would be so much the Lord could do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;God broke me that night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a turning point. Since then, my life has been radically different. I have been involved in the Theatre Arts program at Master’s from that first semester on. I built solid friendships that I still have today. My sophomore year I went through the Israel Bible Extension program (IBEX) and spent three months studying in the Holy Land. My junior year I became an RA. My senior year, as an RA again, I have had the privilege of serving under Resident Director Annelise Wright. She is that same person who was my RA freshman year. In total, some of the sweetest moments have been created here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In looking back, the temptation would be to say that it has all been rainbows and sunshine and The Master’s University is the best place on earth. It’s not. Some semesters have been brutal. They have presented some of the hardest trials I’ve ever gone through. I have lived around and gone to school with about 1,000 other fallen beings. I have sinned and been sinned against. Master’s, as shocking as it may be, is not perfect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, the Lord has used this university in amazing ways. I have been given the foundational understanding of what it is to be a believer. In spite of my selfish desires, times of idolatry and impatience with fellow believers, God has worked. He has taught me who He is through the work of His Spirit in my life. He has shown me the preciousness of His Word. He has displayed the importance of the church. He has revealed my dire need for absolute dependence on Him. He has kept His treasure in this jar of clay so that His surpassing power would only be attributed to Him and never to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My prayer for the school is that it would keep Christ at the center, as it has already done for 90 years. That it would be focused on how we are presenting the gospel, both to the world and to each other. I pray this school would be unified, under the sole basis of the gospel, no matter the dorm, state of origin, race, gender, sport, upbringing, etc. For if we have the gospel in common, we have everything in common. For His glory, and His glory alone.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Sabrina Michael</name></author><category term="bible" /><category term="blake" /><category term="fun" /><summary type="html">Master’s was my last choice. Not only was it my last choice, but it was the only choice I tried to run away from.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/Parallax_Focus.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">TMU Students Present Research at Nationally Recognized Science Conference</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/news/coffee" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="TMU Students Present Research at Nationally Recognized Science Conference" /><published>2017-02-13T22:15:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-02-13T22:15:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/news/coffee</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/news/coffee">&lt;p&gt;“Research is the undergirding of science… It is a publish or perish field,” said Dr. Joe Francis, chair of The Master’s University Department of Biological and Physical Sciences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This well-known fact among the science community is the driving force behind the Annual West Coast Biological Sciences Undergraduate Research Conference (WCBSURC for short) held April 22, 2017. One of the oldest conferences of its kind, its purpose is to “provide a forum for &lt;em&gt;undergraduate&lt;/em&gt; researchers to present original data they have generated in the fields of biology and biochemistry” (italics added) while fostering intercollegiate interaction among students and faculty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In its 42 years, this conference has brought together participants from 182 institutions in 36 states. This year was the eighth time that students from The Master’s University have presented their own research alongside students from other reputable schools like the University of Southern California, Tulane University, Loyola Marymount University, Arizona State University, Vanguard University and many, many more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We want to help [our students] develop the ability to present their research at a high level and to network,” said Dr. Matt Ingle, a project supervisor and Master’s U professor specializing in parasitology. “For any student going into graduate school, the way to be successful is to have your network as broad as possible. As a grad student you don’t need to have deep relationships, as your research is your own, but you do need to rely on other research to explore your own questions.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After traveling over 6 hours to get to Santa Clara University, four student groups defended their answers to the questions they have been researching for over three months. The projects included:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Quality of Mule Deer Fragmented Habitat in Towsley Canyon of the Santa Monica Mountains Conservancy in Santa Clarita, California”&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Students: Jack Underwood, Ethan Brandt, Ethan Cherry, Abby Televera, Shelly Cruzan, Nellie Covert&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Supervising Professor: Dr. Dennis Englin&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Cold-Case Paleobiology: Investigation of a Pathological Ptersoaur Bone from the Morrison Formation of Colorado”&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Student: Kelly Whitely&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Supervising Professor: Dr. Matt McLain&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Reduction in Intermediate Host Performance After Infection with Hymenolepis Diminuta”&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Students: Keifer Bronstedt, Emily Curtain, James Gilbert and Bethany Brown&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Supervising Professor: Dr. Matt Ingle&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Analysis of the Attack of a Single Wind-Thrown Pine Tree in a Healthy Montane Forest by Several Species of Pine Bark Beetles”&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Student: Bekah Johnson&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Supervising Professor: Dr. Joe Francis&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having done over 26 hours of research on pine bark beetles, Bekah Johnson, who hopes to be an entomologist one day, expressed how “small, intricate and elaborate (the bugs) are. It is so impressive—the Lord’s work in creating these tiny and sometimes large insects. I love studying these intricacies and how they interact in the world around them.” Her project analyzes the arrival of different beetle species—before and after a pine tree has fallen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kelly Whitely, who worked under TMU’s resident paleontologist Dr. Matt McLain, explained her project: “(it) combines diagnostics, mystery-solving, and flying reptiles—how much more interesting could it get?” Having thoroughly enjoyed the novelty of researching pathologies on an extinct creature, she was excited to share what she had learned. “…regardless of the amount of research you do,” she said, “there is always the possibility of getting several questions you don’t know the answer to—the thought of not having an answer makes me nervous.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that nervousness and feeling of inadequacy is exactly what Dr. Francis hoped would come of this research class and attendance at the conference. “…undergraduate education is still a one-way communication system: teacher to student,” he said. “There are advantages to that but having that research experience shows (to grad schools) a student who is presented with a problem and has to solve it on their own. We (faculty) can’t tell you everything about it because that’s the nature of research; you’re supposed to discover something new.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, many undergraduate programs do not have the ability to allow students to conduct research, as they lack the capacity to host them. Scientific research in college requires faculty supervision and many larger schools do not have enough faculty to support the numerous student groups. As most graduate institutions strongly recommend research experience, the lack thereof becomes a detriment when undergraduates begin pursuing graduate studies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not the case at The Master’s University.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a course specifically set aside for individual or group research supported by a faculty member, TMU students are given the freedom to plan and structure their research. Funded by The Centers of Excellence—a new program dedicated to investing and developing core academic areas—and the Shamrock Foundation, students are given the responsibility to budget their research and compile and complete the study of their choosing. Their formal presentations at WCBSURC add to and challenge the ongoing dialogue in the world of science.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consistently, the Biological and Physical Sciences Department receives letters from alumni in graduate programs thanking them for their experience at WCBSURC, saying it was the first time they really understood what critical thinking was because their research was so individualized, not based off of a book or an instruction manual. It paved the way for their medical or graduate school career and, ultimately, their future.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Sabrina Michael</name></author><summary type="html">“Research is the undergirding of science… It is a publish or perish field,” said Dr. Joe Francis, chair of The Master’s University Department of Biological and Physical Sciences.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/TMUQuote%20copy.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Dr. John Stead Named TMU Provost</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/news/test" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dr. John Stead Named TMU Provost" /><published>2017-01-31T01:15:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-01-31T01:15:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/news/test</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/news/test">&lt;p&gt;SANTA CLARITA, CA — The Master’s University is pleased to announce the appointment of Dr. John Stead to the position of Senior Vice President and Provost. With a doctorate from the University of Southern California in the triumvirate of American politics, political theory and comparative politics, Stead has taught at Master’s U as a professor of history and political studies for 47 years, serving as the Vice President for Academic Affairs for over 21 of those years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;University President John MacArthur is “thankful to have John (Stead) move into this role that he is so highly qualified to fill due to his education, history at the university and long-standing commitment to Christ. He is a highly respected educator in the echelons of academia, as well as a favorite of the students with his wisdom and personal interest in their lives.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stead is looking forward to working alongside MacArthur, his life-long friend. A witness to much of the university’s history, he remembers the first accreditation in 1975, MacArthur’s inauguration as president when Los Angeles Baptist College became The Master’s College in 1985, and then the institution’s transition to The Master’s University this past year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The challenge of continually supporting and strengthening of our faculty and staff, and most importantly, upholding the gospel as the sure foundation of the university is my foremost commitment,” said Stead, speaking to his new role. “Ultimately, there is no university without our beloved students. They are what drives me to help make this a place that honors the gospel by giving them the opportunity for a Christ-centered education, equipping them with a Christian worldview and preparing them to serve in the church, workplace and home.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.masters.edu/media/869831/wow_89_stead_teaching_fxd.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;alt&quot; height=&quot;36px&quot; width=&quot;36px&quot; /&gt;
This new role for Dr. Stead follows the recent announcement by the university’s Executive Vice President, Dr. Lee Duncan that he will be leaving at the end of this school year to move back into the world of accreditation. Dr. Duncan recently wrote, “I miss being out in Christian schools and teaching them how to use the accreditation process to improve what they are doing. Therefore, after much prayer, I have made the difficult decision to leave TMU to take an opportunity with the Association of Christian Schools International (ACSI).” While excited to welcome Dr. Stead as our Provost we are grateful for the leadership and faithfulness of Dr. Duncan during his years at Master’s U.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The university will continue to flourish under the leadership of one of its most-loved professors and administrators. Eager to continue serving the faculty, staff and students, Stead will assume this new role following TMU’s 90th Commencement Ceremony on May 5, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Sabrina Michael</name></author><summary type="html">SANTA CLARITA, CA — The Master’s University is pleased to announce the appointment of Dr. John Stead to the position of Senior Vice President and Provost. With a doctorate from the University of Southern California in the triumvirate of American politics, political theory and comparative politics, Stead has taught at Master’s U as a professor of history and political studies for 47 years, serving as the Vice President for Academic Affairs for over 21 of those years.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/WelcomeWeb3.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Stumbling Across the Gospel in the Jungle</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/news/TMU" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Stumbling Across the Gospel in the Jungle" /><published>2017-01-31T01:15:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-01-31T01:15:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/news/TMU</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/news/TMU">&lt;p&gt;Article By: Nathan Parsons (Class of 2018)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Photos By: Mark Finster (Class of 2017)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Jan. 3, 1956, five evangelical missionaries began to set up camp on Palm Beach, an isolated sandbar on the Curaray river in Ecuador. Shouting basic Waodaniphrases into the jungle, Jim Elliot, Nate Saint, Ed McCully, Peter Fleming and Roger Youderian were determined to bring the gospel to this unreached Ecuadorian tribe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around 3:00 p.m. on Jan. 8, six Waodanitribesmen emerged from the jungle, gesturing to the missionaries. By 3:30 p.m., the bodies of all five men lay strewn across the sand, brutally speared to death.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*****&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago, Mark Finster, Mitch Clevidence and I boarded a plane at LAX and flew to Ecuador for our TMU spring break. We planned to rent a car, drive around, shoot video for our video journalism class, eat local food and avoid suffering from altitude sickness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We did all those things, save avoiding the altitude sickness (sorry, Mark). We experienced the predictably unpredictable mishaps that go along with three 20-somethings driving around South America, including taking the “scenic route” that left us with our car stuck in the mud. If Juan and Juan Carlos hadn’t shown up with their 4x4 to pull us out, we’d probably still be there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before leaving for our trip, we talked through the story of the five missionaries martyred on Palm Beach. When Life magazine published a 10-page article on their mission to reach the Waodaniand their deaths in 1956, their martyrdom quickly gripped the fascination of American evangelicalism and continues to do so today. Between reading Nate Saint’s biography four times and watching “End of the Spear”(2006) more than one should, it’s safe to say their story saturated my childhood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.masters.edu/media/869837/ecuador-project-15.jpg?width=500&amp;amp;height=325.3333333333333&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;With their stories in the back of our minds, we made sure to schedule a stop in Shell. Named after the British oil company, Shell served as the home base for the missionaries’ operations. Nate Saint’s (refurbished) house still stands not more than 500 yards away from the airstrip he used fly his yellow Piper Cub into the jungle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Driving by the airstrip was meaningful; barreling down the runway in a six-seat bush plane was another thing entirely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the connections of some missionaries Mark knows, less than a day after arriving in Shell we found ourselves flying out to the Waodanivillage of Tiweano. As I looked down at the mountainous, jagged jungle terrain, I understood why Tiweano remains unconnected by road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Warm Waodanitribespeople and stifling humidity met us when we landed on the grass airstrip in Tiweano. Mincayeand Mineawa—two Waodanimen who flew out with us and graciously acted as our guides—helped the pilot reposition the plane and led us to the village’s church building.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the five missionaries died on Palm Beach, their mission did not end; it signaled the beginning. A few years later, Elizabeth Elliot (Jim’s widow) and Rachel Saint (Nate’s sister) successfully made peaceful contact with the Waodani, eventually living with them and evangelizing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The forgiveness shown by Elizabeth and Rachel stood in sharp contrast to the revenge killings previously intrinsic to Waodaniculture and resulted in many tribespeople coming to Christ. Culturally accepted murder ceased almost immediately. Churches sprang up within the tribe, and some of the men who murdered the missionaries in 1956 became church elders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.masters.edu/media/869838/ecuador-project-16-1.jpg?width=500&amp;amp;height=333.3333333333333&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of these men, Dyuwi, was more than happy to speak with us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It gives me great joy that when I die, I will go to heaven,” said Dyuwi, now 82. “Jesus saved me and will not let me go.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking in Waodanithrough a translator, Dyuwi’s eyes lit up when asked about what continues to drive him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I have a great passion for this third generation of Waodani…to know Christ. I fear that when they go outside the tribe, they fall away and turn towards the temptations of the world.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still in a subtle state of shock after having the opportunity to talk to Dyuwi, we reboarded our prop plane for the 10-minute flight to the village of Tunempadi. After landing and disembarking, Mincaye and Mineawa led us down a dirt path towards the shore of the Curaray river.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We emerged from the path within one hundred yards of “the spot.” The constant flow of the Curaray has since eroded the specific sand bar that made up the original Palm Beach, but the spot has not been forgotten.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I’ve returned from Ecuador, a lot of people have asked me “what it was like” to stand where those five missionaries died. To be sure, I felt a sense of history and solemnness. But in the end, it’s just a beach in the middle of the jungle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.masters.edu/media/869835/ecuador-project-6.jpg?width=500&amp;amp;height=306.66666666666663&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I stood on the beach and looked at Mark, Mitch and three Christian Waodani, I realized the story lies in the present, not the past. Or, more to the point, the story demonstrates the gospel’s power to transform individual lives and cultures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As American Christians lament Western society’s increasing secularism, it is easy to become fatalistic and forget that the gospel comes not “in word only, but also in power and in the Holy Spirit” (1 Thess. 1:5). It can transform an isolated, fear-driven tribal society, where 70 percent of men could expect to be murdered at some point, to one that stands as a spiritual leader among Ecuadorian tribes, all within a few decades.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The gospel transforms lives so dramatically that Dyuwi—a murderer of the men who brought the faith he now follows—can look Mark square in the face and joyfully tell him that because of the death and resurrection of Jesus Christ, he is forgiven in the eyes of God.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we flew back to Los Angeles, I could not help but think of 2 Corinthians 5:17, where the Apostle Paul—a murderer himself—tells the previously pagan Corinthians that “if anyone is in Christ, he is a new creation. The old has passed away; behold, the new is come.” Whether in the jungles of Ecuador or on the campus of The Master’s University, the gospel has the same effect: it convicts, saves and transforms, regardless of human effort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before leaving for spring break, Mark, Mitch and I figured we’d experience Ecuador’s splendor, whether that came in the natural landscapes, the people or the food. None of that, however, compared with the beauty of the gospel.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Sabrina Michael</name></author><summary type="html">Article By: Nathan Parsons (Class of 2018)</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/WEB_TMU.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The University Exchange</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/news/the-university-exchange" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The University Exchange" /><published>2017-01-31T00:56:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-01-31T00:56:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/news/the-university-exchange</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/news/the-university-exchange">&lt;p&gt;Deciding where to go to college is one of the most important choices we make in life. Wanting to be successful—which looks different for everyone—can be a driving factor in choosing a school. For the first time we are on our own, every decision impacting the person we will become.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a high school athlete, it was so easy for me to get caught up in the ambition to play for a Division I school. I believed I would be defined by what college or division I played in, and it was a major factor in my choice: “Do I really want to go play baseball for this tiny NAIA school? What would my friends think? What would my high school coach think?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In retrospect, I know I could not have answered these questions without the influence of my brother, Steven. The Lord divinely placed him at The Master’s University two years before me and opened up a door that would change me in many ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I saw firsthand what TMU had done for my brother academically, athletically and spiritually. So, choosing TMU myself became an easy decision. I saw how Master’s played an active role in molding him into the man of God that he is, I watched how all his like-minded friends pushed him to be like Christ and I noticed the success he was having playing baseball while having fun and still pursuing excellence in the classroom. His experience was exactly what I wanted, and I knew I could not get that anywhere but Master’s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could not play for a better coach or with better teammates, athletes who love the Lord and still have the passion and desire to win games. I get to play for a coach that pushes me on the field and, more importantly, pushes us all to do everything for the glory of God.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coach Monte Brooks has been one of the greatest blessings of my life, exhorting all of us to “love the Lord your God with all your heart, and with all your soul, and with all your mind” (Matthew 22:37). This is our team verse and Coach has used it to teach us that we must become slaves to Christ if we want to be excellent and successful in all that we do as Christians.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The baseball team has opened one of the largest doors to my spiritual growth. On this team I have been tested and established lifelong friendships with guys focused on Christ. If I had chosen another school, I would have missed out on my two favorite memories as a Mustang: throwing a perfect game with my brother playing in the outfield and being a part of a team that reached the World Series.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am beyond grateful that the Lord’s plan for me included attending and playing baseball here. This university has completely shattered the roof of my expectations and has influenced my life more than I could have imagined, all by the grace of God. I am forever thankful for The Master’s University.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Sabrina Michael</name></author><summary type="html">Deciding where to go to college is one of the most important choices we make in life. Wanting to be successful—which looks different for everyone—can be a driving factor in choosing a school. For the first time we are on our own, every decision impacting the person we will become.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/TMUQuote%20copy.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to Jekyll!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/news/welcome-to-jekyll" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to Jekyll!" /><published>2017-01-12T21:51:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-01-12T21:51:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/news/welcome-to-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/news/welcome-to-jekyll">&lt;p&gt;“I want to mimic what Jake [Litwin] said on Monday and thank the Bible Department for allowing me to have this opportunity,” said Nate Youtzy, his deep voice booming as he opened his Spurgeonfest sermon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Pastor John Piper, Charles H. Spurgeon is “considered by many to be one of the greatest preachers since the days of the apostles,” having preached over 600 times before the age of 20. Named in reference to this famous and very quotable preacher, Spurgeonfest is a week that has been set aside annually since the early 1990s to enable senior Bible majors at The Master’s University the opportunity to preach in chapel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Biblical Studies Department along with the leadership of Student Life “thought it would be a good idea to have a few senior Bible Majors preach. They do a similar thing at the seminary and we thought we would do the same,” explained Dr. Tom Halstead, chair of the Biblical Studies Department.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nominated and selected by the Bible faculty based on their achievement in the Sermon Preparation course, reputation in the department and credibility around campus, students consider it quite an honor to speak to their peers and represent the department. The two speakers selected this year? Jake Litwin and Nate Youtzy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.masters.edu/media/869762/spurgeonfest.jpg?width=500&amp;amp;height=320&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Litwin, a resident assistant in C.W. Smith Hall, spoke Monday using 1 Corinthians 1:18-31 as his text, reminding himself and his audience to not follow the world’s wisdom but be confident in the wisdom of God and His saving gospel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Our boasting is in Christ alone,” he said, “because He gives us wisdom, righteousness, sanctification and redemption.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Youtzy, having been guided by his own time in the Word, spoke from Matthew 16:24-28 describing what it looks like to be a disciple of God. Nate plans on continuing his education at The Master’s Seminary this fall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both students were encouraged by the eruption of applause and affirmation from their peers as the sermons ended.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They did “an equally fabulous job,” according to Halstead, who continued, “I am so proud of them and thought it couldn’t have been better. That just shows the time and work of our faculty as well. Jake and Nate were good examples for us this year.”&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Blake Noll</name></author><summary type="html">“I want to mimic what Jake [Litwin] said on Monday and thank the Bible Department for allowing me to have this opportunity,” said Nate Youtzy, his deep voice booming as he opened his Spurgeonfest sermon.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/TMUQuote%20copy.jpg" /></entry></feed>
